250 Ocean Parkway #6G • Brooklyn, NY 11218 215-292-2193 • colin@colinabartlett.com

PROFILE

I'm a Senior Ruby developer with 15 years experience building web applications and managing software development projects and teams. I have full-stack experience and am a dedicated practitioner of TDD. I enjoy providing business value to stakeholders beyond just writing code.

EXPERIENCE

Co-owner at Kinetic Web Solutions, Limerick, PA (Jan 2001 - Jun 2010)

In 2001, I founded a web development firm. I took on a partner and grew it to 10 full-time employees. In 2006, I converted our operations from Microsoft ASP to Ruby on Rails and transitioned us to a Rails consultancy. I was responsible for all day-to-day operations, sales, marketing, and project management. I was a developer and oversaw all development, engineering, and systems administration.

Senior Consultant at Xforty Technologies, Limerick, PA (Jun 2010 - Sep 2011)

In 2010, I sold Kinetic and began consulting with friends at Xforty. I worked on several Rails applications and dabbled in some PHP and other projects. In January 2011, I obtained Loosecubes as a customer and moved to New York to contract with them full-time for 9 months.

Lead Developer at Loosecubes, Brooklyn, NY (Jan 2011 - July 2012)

Loosecubes hired me in September 2011 to lead their development team. I was involved with nearly all aspects of their Rails application since the beginning. For a time, I was their sole developer and, for a time, I worked along side an outsourced team. I helped to train numerous newly-hired engineers and shape development strategy for this early-stage start-up.

Director of Engineering at AppStack, Temecula, CA (October 2012 - Present)

I started at AppStack as a Senior Developer and eventually moved up to manage the engineering team. As Director of Engineering, I not only contribute daily to the codebase, but manage team direction and goals, mentor junior developers, interact with management and stakeholders, and generally keep the ship afloat.

SKILLS

Expert level Ruby and Rails experience. Full stack developer proficient in JavaScript. Specializing in Test Driven Development, with significant experience introducing teams to TDD best-practices. Advanced Git, Rspec, and Cucumber experience and intermediary Linux systems administration abilities. Extremely picky about well-formed git commits.

COMMUNITY

Organizer of the Philly on Rails Ruby user group 2008 to 2011 and frequent presenter. Contributor to Rails and other open source projects.

EDUCATION

Business Major at Northeastern University, Boston, MA, (2001)

INTERESTS

Traveling, cooking, reading, Russia. Proficient in conversational Russian.